(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T10:22:07.035675",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
また悪い夢を見た。
Another bad dream.
惨様な現場が日常の探偵という職業には、悪夢は付き物と言ってもいいでしょう。
Perhaps nightmares are the penalty a detective pays for in a gruesome business.
だが、気にしている場合ではない。
So be it. She's not about to stop.
彼女のもとに、また新たな事件が舞い込んできているからだ。
Not when there are new cases to be solved.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? If you're dealing with woes,
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even if you're not human,
Be happy! 踏み迷わず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep on trying and aim high.
生きているんだし目を逸した過去も
Living life, turning away from the past,
退屈な未来もカウンセリング
counseling that boring future too.
やれやれ古今東西ピースピース
Oh well, far and wide, peace, peace!
Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy!
Undead! ねぇ一体どうして
Undead! Hey, why is it...
戦っているようなそんな気がするの
feeling like I'm fighting something?
触れられない 触れたくもない
A past self I can't touch, don't want to touch...
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分
me, me, me, me!
もうとっくに死んでいる透明な亡霊と対決
confronting a transparent ghost already dead long ago.
幼くて痛い記憶の奥残念?もう居ないのにあれ?
Childish, painful memories deep inside... gone already? Huh?
そっちが良い?アイロニね透かされているのは
Is that better? Irony, seeing right through...
現在の自分?ナンセンス消せないレターYes
...the current me? Nonsense, a letter that won't fade, Yes!
要はコンプレックス取り憑かれているみたい
The point is, I'm possessed by a complex,
巻き付いたまま離れない 在りし日の自分
wrapped tightly and won't let go, my past self.
Undead 死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
Undead, you're not dead, you and your chains!
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep on changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するな幸せになろうと
Don't settle for unhappiness, don't accept being sad.
しないなんて卑俗だこの世この世は
Not trying to be happy is vulgar, this world...
奇奇怪怪ファンタジー 次は鬼が出るか
...is one bizarre fantasy, what's next, a demon or a snake?
蛇が出るか 出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting and finally starting the story,
さぁ 人か化け物か 閑話休題ピースピース
Now, human or monster, back on topic, peace, peace!
Past & future Can't change the past
Past & future Run for the future
カットイン 何だかどうして 未来になんぞ何の希望もない
Cut-in, somehow why is there no hope for the future?
期待出来ないような気がしても もう随分生きている
Even if it feels like there's nothing to expect, I've lived long enough.
既視感とテンプレで食傷 珍しい出来事の気配もない
Sick of déjà vu and templates, no sign of anything rare.
残念 積んだ経験の因果 形態化された神話と退屈な進化
Regrettable cause and effect, mythos and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちまった慣れちまった
The point is I want a thrill, I'm bored, I'm used to it.
なんて整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス 覆われていくみたい
Guidance smoothing out, compliance increasing, covered up.
吸い尽くして あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
Sucking it all dry, this, that, and everything tastes the same.
Undead 死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
Undead, you're not dead, you and your chains!
何時の世も 過去も未来も 現在にあるんだよ
In any era, past and future are right in the present.
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Truthfully fulfill your life, aim for a happy ending!
Undead 死んじゃいない おわりに言っているんだよ
Undead, you're not dead, I'm telling this to you!
幸せを諦めてしまうような 人であれだった
Someone who gives up on happiness...
苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ 死んでいるも同然
Enduring suffering is practically being dead.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? If you're dealing with woes,
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even if you're not human,
Be happy! 踏み迷わず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep on trying and aim high.
溺れそうになる不幸せも
Even if you're drowning in unhappiness,
掴み取る幸せも
or seizing true happiness,
全部自分次第なんだよ
it's all up to you!
ユニバーサル 全てを包み込んで
Universal, embracing everything...
ピースピース
Peace, peace!
Past & future Can't change the past
Past & future Run for the future
どこかで集まってごらん 悩める人の子も
Gather around somewhere, you worried souls,
生き延びていこう この怪奇譚
Let's survive this bizarre tale!
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? If you're dealing with a lotta woes
Unlucky? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Then you got to listen very close
Be happy! 怠らず目指せよ
Be happy! Keep on trying, never give up
生きているんだし 目を逸らした過去も
Don't forget that you're alive... The past you've been running from
退屈な未来も カウンセリング
That boring future yet to come, still counseling you
やれやれ古今東西
Oh my, oh my, universal
ピースピース
Peace, peace, yeah
Unhappy?
Unlucky?
Be happy!
Undead
Undead, oh
ねえ 何故どうして戦っているようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, why does it feel like there's a fight going on inside?
触れられない 触れたくもない過去の自分
Past version of me that I can't touch nor want to touch
自分 自分 自分と もうとっくに死んでる透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting the transparent ghost of my long-dead self
幼気で痛い記憶の奥 ざわざわ
Deep inside childish and painful memories
残念? もう居ないの? あれ? そっちが良い?
Saddening? Nowhere to be seen. Say what? Way better then?
アイロニー 透かされているのは現在の自分?
Irony. They all see the me of the past when looking at me now
ナンセンス 消えないレター
Nonsense. Label I can't erase
Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Yes! In essence, a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
It's almost like something's possessing me
巻き付いたまま離れない 在りし日の自分
It is wrapping tight around, the self I used to be
Undead 死んじまいない
Undead, still alive
お前とお前の連鎖
Time is a chain of your own path
生きていることは 繋がり続けることだ
To be alive is to always embrace your inner changes
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness, don't be complacent
幸せになろうとなんて卑怯だ
Not even trying to be happy, you coward
この世 この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world is one odd, one odd fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Who knows what is coming up next, a monster or a snake?
出会って遭遇してやっと始まる物語
This is a story starting after that encounter, finally
さあ人か化け物か
With people or monsters
閑話休題
Back on topic
ピースピース
Peace, peace, yeah
Past & future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
Ah...
ダメダメダメ 脳味噌の中から「やめろ馬鹿」
No, no, no, my brain screams, "Don't do it, you idiot!"
Darlin' baby darlin' I love you
時めき雪あしあすてっぷ
It's a philosophy that's got me giddy and sparking
じっと見つめられてるだけ
The way you look up at me is so adorable
瞬間でるもどうだんしゃ
It just kills me, it's almost illegal
しかばねも同然 お前らここに登場
Scattering madness, I'd squandered it all before I knew it
一か八か死なない症候群
And your existence is to blame
何がしようにか触れるくらい
I'm heartsick and it's painful
バラまくラッシュ 気付けば閉じ
My head's severed from my body
この世に生まれた君が悪い
I love yous spew from my carotid artery
やたらとしんどい恋わずらい
And it's Iris Out
IRIS OUT いっそどうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What the hell am I supposed to do about these feelings?
暴れ出す心臓皿の目が溶けて
In the back of my ribs sugar crystals melt...
ケロンになりそう どこか端らいで溢れそう
Pupils dilated to the max, I feel like I'm about to drown
今この世で君だけが正解
In this world right now, you're my one-and-only perfect answer
Darlin' darlin'
振り返ることもない
Even if I flip over, belly-up
君だけルールは度外視
I still couldn't win, the rules don't apply to you
四つも恐らく黒しか無い勝ちようがない
Opened with four black Othello discs, you dominate
君が笑顔ならまたバラけだすデパ地下に捨て駒もうしわけねえ
You flung an Avada Kedavra at me with a smile
射抜いて 貫いて 撃ち抜いて頂戴
Got a stigma on my forehead, my bad. Pierce me with an arrow...
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣い
The way you look up at me is so adorable
何がしようにか触れるくらい バラまくラッシュ
It just kills me, scattering madness before I knew it
気付けば閉じ この世に生まれた君が悪い
And your existence is to blame, heartsick and painful
なんでもいい なんでもいい
Don't care if it's fake, give me everything
今君と名付づいてるすべてが欲しい
I love yous spew from my carotid artery
ケロンになりそう
And it's Iris Out
IRIS OUT いっそどうしよう この思いをどうしよう
What the hell am I supposed to do about these feelings?
暴れ出す心臓皿の目が溶けて
In the back of my ribs sugar crystals melt...
ケロンになりそう どこか端らいで溢れそう
Pupils dilated to the max, I feel like I'm about to drown
今この世で君だけが正解
In this world right now, you're my one-and-only perfect answer
Darlin' darlin'
ある殺人事件を調べてほしいという匿名の人からの依頼。
Like this one: An anonymous plea for help in the investigation of a murder.
手紙に被害者の情報はほとんどなく、ましてや犯人の情報は皆無であった。
The letter had little on the victim and nothing on the killer.
あまりに不可解な謎の手紙。イタズラの可能性もあるけど…
A letter too mysterious and cryptic. It could even be a prank.
おや？
Huh?
おはよう、アーニャ！依頼された絵が完成したよ～。
Good morning, Anya! I finished your commission~
一伊那栖
Ninomae Ina'nis.
この町一番の肖像画家だ。
The greatest portrait artist on this side of the tracks.
あの…私の顔に何かついてます？
Um... is there something on my face?
事件の手がかりがない以上、解決の糸口を見つけるには彼女の才能を頼る必要があった。
With no leads, the detective needed a talent like that to jumpstart her investigation.
アーニャ？
Anya?
とはいえこういった事件では、誰もが容疑者になりうる。
Then again, in a case like this, anyone could be the killer.
そう、この純粋で可憐なイナでさえ——
What if sweet, innocent Ina—
わぁーっ！
WAH!
うわっ！
Ah!
ごめんなさい。じーっと見られてたからつい…。どうかしましたか？
Sorry, but you were just staring at me. Is everything okay?
いや別に…それっぽい雰囲気を出そうとしてただけ。
Yeah, I'm just building atmosphere.
それより、頼んだ絵はできた？
Uh, anyway, you did the picture I asked for?
できました～！
Yeah!
描きましたけど、それ誰なんですか？
Who's this a picture of anyway?
誰の写真？
いま調べている事件の被害者だよ。
The victim from a case I'm working.
あっ、報酬はいつもの値段でいいよね？
Anyway, you're charging the standard fee, right?
悪いけど今回はツケにしといて。
Sorry, but can you put it on my tab?
でも前回もツケって言ってましたよね…。
But you put the last one on your tab too...
じゃあイナは特別に…1回だけタダで依頼を受けてあげるから。
Maybe we could do a trade then? I'll solve one case for you for free.
それよりも…歌がいいな～。
Ooorrr... I'll trade you for a song~
はい？
Huh?
だって！アニャさん最近ずっと怖い顔してますよ。たまには息抜きしないと。私と1曲歌ってくれたら、絵は差し上げます。どうですか？
Come on! You've been so serious lately. You gotta get loose sometimes. So one song with me, and you get to keep the picture. That's the deal!
そこまで言うなら…歌ってやるか！
If that's what you want, then alright!
大きい白いキャンバスに 虚構のコラージュを貼るよ
On a big white canvas, I paste a collage of fiction
どこからでもキレイに映る 誇張された天使が居たよ
There was an exaggerated angel that looked stunning from every angle
薔薇人歪んだ正しくなくても見えた
A rose, a person distorted, even if they weren't right I could still see them
生きるため立ち寄った美術館のセザンヌに
In the Cézanne at the art museum I stopped by to stay alive
なにもわからないな まだ知らずにいても描けた
I don't understand anything, but even without knowing I managed to paint
赤ざっと塗り込んだ バカ きっとそうだった
I kept plastering red all over — idiot, I surely did
ヒドい筆の絵画 だけどそこがいいな
A painting with terrible brushwork, but that's what's good about it
くぐらない線だな そのまま
Such meaningless lines, just as they are
ああ
Ah
切って貼った皮
The skin that's cut and pasted
裂けて見えた痣
The bruises seen when it's torn
ララ ラン ラララ
La la lan lalala
笑うように浮いた アバラ
Floating ribs that seem to laugh
ぎゅって抱いた空
I held the emptiness tight
だって泣いたから
Because I had cried
ララ ラン ラララ なげく壁に 描いたパブロ・ピカソ
La la lan lalala, painted on the grieving wall — Pablo Picasso
なぜか私のことだなって眺めちゃんたよ
Somehow I found myself thinking 'this is about me', as I gazed
これが欲しいなって感じたら
It made me feel 'I want this'
セザンヌの絵をキボヌン なんてね
I want a Cézanne painting, just kidding
老人がとなりでじっと見てたよ
An old man beside me was staring
欺瞞ウソ若さならば
Deception and lies — if it's youth
本物の意味あるのかな
I wonder if there's any meaning to the real thing
真実抱いたまま 腐り落ちて床で死んでた
Whilst holding the truth in your arms, it rotted away and died on the floor
赤ざっと塗り込んだ やっぱずっと良かった
I kept plastering red all over — that was the best after all
イヤらしい線だな 今もう
Such nasty lines, even now, ah
ああ
Ah
切って貼った皮
The skin that's cut and pasted
咲いて散った花
The flowers bloomed and scattered
ララ ラン ラララ
La la lan lalala
笑うように見えた カラダ
A body that seemed to laugh
ぎゅって抱いた空
I held the emptiness tight
だって泣いたから
Because I had cried
ララ ラン ラララ なげく壁に 描いたパブロ・ピカソ
La la lan lalala, painted on the grieving wall — Pablo Picasso
わたしウソのピカソ
I, the Picasso of lies
やっと来た。
Finally.
こんな不気味な場所で待たせないでほしいんだけど。
This is a creepy place to make someone wait.
現場を調べたらKFPの近くに寄るから、店の近くで待っててって言ったのに。
I told you I'd come to the nearby KFP after investigating the crime scene.
そんなの無理！
Not a chance!
アンタと話すだけでもイヤなのに、話してるところを見られたりしたらそれこそ最悪。
It's bad enough I have to talk to you. I don't want others to be around to see it.
そんなアンタが手を貸してくれるなんて意外だけどね。
I'm surprised you're willing to cooperate in the first place.
それは…例の殺人事件以降、いろいろ妙なことが起こってるの。
Yeah, well, ever since the murder, weird things have been happening.
アンタが解決してくれるなら、こうやって会うのもやむなしよ。イヤだけど。
I figure if you can help solve it, then it's worth the trouble of meeting with you. Just barely.
妙なことが起こってる？
What weirdness?
「人の形をした黒い影が見えた」って報告が、うちの従業員からちょくちょく出てるの。
Some of my employees have been complaining about seeing a shadowy figure.
話によれば、最初は夢の中にそれが現れたんだけど、今は起きてる時も見えてる――
They say it started with bad dreams, but now some are seeing it even when they're—
アーニャ！
Anya!
だ…大丈夫。それより…これ見て。
I'm... fine, don't worry about me. Look at this.
まったくもう、アンタはいつも大げさすぎ…ん？
Hmph. 'Course. You're just always being overly dramatic... huh?
おかしいな。現場の証拠品は警察が全部回収したはずなのに。
Weird. I figured the cops would have already collected all the evidence.
この近くに住んでるKFPの従業員で、被害者のことを知る者は？
Did any of your employees who live nearby know the victim?
いない。
Nope.
分かった。新しい情報が入ったらまた教えて。
Alright. Let me know if you hear anything else.
ちょっと待った！
Wait!
それだけ？私の時間を奪っておいてタダで帰るつもり？
That's it? You're not even gonna compensate me for my time?
従業員のそのためとか思いきや、結局カネかい。タダ働きはしない主義なの。
I thought you were doing this to help your employees. I'm still a businesswoman.
いま持ち合わせがないんだけど、代わりに歌で支払っていうのはどう？
Well, I don't have any cash on me, but I can pay you in song.
ウソでしょ？歌うの？アンタと？
Seriously? You think I'd want to sing? With you?
イナは歌で喜んでくれたけどなー。ただ、イナと歌うのは楽しいけど、
Ina accepted payment in song. But then, singing with her is fun...
ただ、イナと歌うのは楽しいけど、キアラと歌っててもなあ…
But then, singing with her is fun... With you...
それどういう意味？私の歌じゃダメってこと？やってやろうじゃないの！ほら、さっさと歌うよ！
With me, what? You don't think I'm good enough for you? Let's go, punk! You and me, right now!
全部全部アンタのせいだ
It's all, all your fault.
嘔吐が出るくらいにウザッたいわ
You're such a pain, it makes me wanna hurl.
何かにすがってへずって
Clinging to things, fawning over things...
期待したアタシが馬鹿だった
I was stupid to think I'd get something out of it.
ご機嫌伺いの八方美人
I'm a people-pleaser coming to pay my respects,
それ故にアンチな一生 gimme
So gimme a hater life.
浅いキャパシティ 毎回大きに
I've got a shallow capacity, thanks for your patronage.
つまるとこ人生ずっと地味
Basically, my life's always been drab.
「鬱陶しい！」 「痛々しい！」
“How hateful! How pathetic!”
無視出来ないのが一層
The way I can't ignore you makes it worse -
腹立たしい 逆立たしい
How maddening, how vexing.
そろそろ飽きた自画自賛に
I've had just about enough of blowing my own horn.
(look around ! !)
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of like is apathy
≒繋がれた証
≒ Proof that you're connected.
切り離せない関係
A relationship I can't cut off...
逸らしてしまうタイワ
I'd love to just look away from it.
これは所謂ヘイトスピーチ
This is what you'd call hate speech.
匿名性の声明を生命に乗せてんだ
We're posting these anonymous declarations onto our very lives.
鳴り止まないサイレン 近づく度に痙攣
We spasm every time those ceaseless sirens draw near.
赤信号にずっと従順です。
We've obeyed red lights all this time.
大体アナタのコト アタシ
Point is, I absolutely -
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイダイキライ
- hate hate hate hate hate you.
omg 情けない 最早
Omg, how pathetic, I just wanna say -
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
- bye bye bye bye bye already.
脳内も予測不能 故に
Can't tell what's going on in that mind, and thus there's -
解解解解解はない
- no no no no no solution.
どうだい？アタシのコト アタシ
How's it? Do you absolutely -
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイダイキライになった？
- hate hate hate hate me now?
ア ァ 百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, all pain and no gain, nothing, not see.
モシタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
It'd be like nicotine to think back on the what-ifs.
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス凡ミス
Going back because I missed you was a stupid mistake, mistake.
センキュー 反面教師
Thanks for being a great bad example.
後味一生消えてくんないわ
You've left an aftertaste that won't ever disappear.
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, what a good girl.
笑顔振り撒き パラパラ いい子ね
Strewing your smile around, scatter scatter, what a good girl.
だけど だけど その本性は？
But you know, but you know, what's your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？(笑)はぁ。
Can you even tell right from wrong? (lol) sigh.
減点方式で取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Shrouded by an environment that traps people with demerits.
生涯、「痛い！痛い！痛い！」も聞かれないわ！って
“Ow! Ow! Ow!” you cry, “but no one asks!” you'll say for life, but -
当然の報いにくらっときちゃった
serves you right.
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors.
実のところ 依存は両方です
The truth is, it's codependence.
シャットダウンしても付き纏う
Even if you shut it all down, it still sticks around.
己の弱さが不甲斐ない
My weakness feels so cowardly.
全部全部アンタのせいって
It's all, all your fault I say.
嘔吐が出るくらいに止まないわ
It won't stop, it makes me wanna hurl.
いっそ事 切り離した方が楽なのに
Rather, it would've been so much easier if I could've cut it off.
大体アナタのコト アタシ
Point is, I absolutely -
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイダイキライ
- hate hate hate hate hate you.
omg 情けない 最早
Omg, how pathetic, I just wanna say -
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
- bye bye bye bye bye already.
脳内も予測不能 故に
Can't tell what's going on in that mind, and thus there's -
解解解解解はない
- no no no no no solution.
どうだい？アタシのコト アタシ
How's it? Do you absolutely -
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイダイキライになった？
- hate hate hate hate me now?
ア ァ 百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, all pain and no gain, nothing, not see.
モシタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
It'd be like nicotine to think back on the what-ifs.
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス凡ミス
Going back because I missed you was a stupid mistake, mistake.
センキュー 反面教師
Thanks for being a great bad example.
後味一生消えてくんないわ
You've left an aftertaste that won't ever disappear.
全部全部アンタのせいで
It's all, all your fault I say.
隔たるくらいに止まんないわ
It won't stop, it makes me wanna hurl.
いっそのこと切り離した方が
Rather, it would've been so much easier
楽になるなりね
if I could've cut it off.
大体アナタのコト アタシ
Point is, I absolutely -
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイダイキライ
- hate hate hate hate hate you.
omg 情けない 最早
Omg, how pathetic, I just wanna say -
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
- bye bye bye bye bye already.
脳内も予測不能 故に
Can't tell what's going on in that mind, and thus there's -
解解解解解はない
- no no no no no solution.
どうだい？アタシのコト アタシ
How's it? Do you absolutely -
ダイダイ ダイダイ ダイダイキライになった？
- hate hate hate hate me now?
ア ァ 百害あって一利ナシ nothing not see
Ah, all pain and no gain, nothing, not see.
モシタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
It'd be like nicotine to think back on the what-ifs.
i miss youって近付いた結末は凡ミス凡ミス
Going back because I missed you was a stupid mistake, mistake.
センキュー 反面教師
Thanks for being a great bad example.
後味一生消えてくんないわ
You've left an aftertaste that won't ever disappear.
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, what a good girl.
笑顔振り撒き パラパラ いい子ね
Strewing your smile around, scatter scatter, what a good girl.
だけど だけど その本性は？
But you know, but you know, what's your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの？(笑)はぁ。
Can you even tell right from wrong? (lol) sigh.
はあ、もう誰なの？
WHAT!
はーい
Come in.
あ、アニャやっほー。
Hey, Anya. Ya doing okay?
大丈夫そう？なんか顔色悪いね。
You look kind of... not great.
大丈夫…じゃあないかもね。
Thanks... maybe not.
ちょっと横になったほうがいいんじゃない？マリオカート走ってあげるから、綿飴の数を数えるといいよ。
You just need sleep! Lie down, and I'll run in circles so you can count me~
心配かけてごめん。でも今寝たらダメなんだ。
Sorry, but not now.
なぜならあともうちょっとでこの事件を解決できそうなんだから！
I'm close to cracking this case wide open!
そーう？
You sure?
そう…かも。そうじゃないかも。
I don't know! Yes? Maybe?
わかんないけど、とりあえずヒントは揃ったんだ。
I do have all the hints...
ほな難しいか。
That doesn't seem very sure...
ワタメ先輩、ほどほどにしておきましょう。
Watame-senpai, I think you're annoying her.
ワタメは悪くないよねぇ？
Watame did nothing wrong.
これが事件を解く鍵なんだ。探偵の直感がそう言ってる。でもDNA鑑定では何もわからなかった。
This is an important clue! I can feel it in my gut, but a DNA trace was a dead end.
じゃあこれは何なんだ？これは何なんだ？
So what does it mean? What does it mean?!
その布でそんなにお困りなら、
That's a mean cloth?
じゃあ、ワタメが食べてあげる！
Oh! I could eat it.
ねえアニャ、それちょっと見せてくれる？
Hey Anya? Can I take a look at that?
この布について分かったことはあるけど…それを教えたら、ちょっと休憩しない？
If I tell you something about this cloth, will you agree to take a break?
一旦仕事の手は止めて、私たちと遊ぼうよ。
Maybe do something fun with us before you go back to work?
じゃあ一緒に歌うでも歌う？この街では情報は歌で買うものみたいだし。
We could sing together. That seems to be the going rate for information around here.
おー、楽しそう！
Oh, that sounds fun!
オッケー。その布には魔力の痕跡を感じるんだ。
Alright... I can sense a magical residue on this cloth.
そんな、バカな。
That can't be true.
忘れたの？アイリスはネフィリム。
Hey, I'm a nephilim, remember?
魔力を聞き取るなんてお手のもの。
We get a bonus to detect magic!
あれ？アーニャもこの布が怪しいと思ってたんじゃないの？
Wait... you already had your suspicions about the cloth, didn't you?
そう、だけどさ。でも、殺人事件と超自然現象なんて混ぜたらだめなやつでしょ？
Yeeeeaaah... but supernatural stuff happening in a murder case? They're not supposed to mix.
そう？でも、そういうアニメとかドラマも…
Really? But in some shows—
まあまあ！物騒な話はそのくらいにして、みんなで歌っちゃおー！
Enough murder talk. Let's sing—
この路地を抜けろ awake now
Kararajo nukero awake now
(僕ら 覚醒 アップデート ey)
(Boku ra kakusei update ey)
ギラギラ 光らせた いいな いいな そのカラット
Gira gira hikaraseta ii na ii na sono carat
目立っちまうな 自然に 視線を 独り占め
Me-tachichau na shizen ni shisen o hakaridori
この手口は 盗めない
Kono tekuchi wa nusumenai
答えなら 「好きだけ」 が極まってくる
Kotae nara "suki dake" ga kiwamatte kuru
一秒前 完全 アップデート ya ya
Ichibyo mae kanzen update ya ya
不安 ぐっばい 自分以外は 敵じゃない
Fuan gubbai jibun igai wa teki ja nai
お利口 御無用 指を立てろ
Onriku omuyō yubi o tatero
ha～ 揺せろ 運命 ah～ あたらしい ウルトラ c
Ha~ yusero unmei ah~ atarashii urutora c
その感情を 燃料に持ち込む 炎上戦 へ全能
Sono kanjō o nenryō ni mochikomu enjō-sen e zen-nō
無謀、体が
Mubō, karada ga
この生き様で make some noise
Kono ikisama de make some noise
見舞う we gotta go メディカル ボイス
Mimai we gotta go mediakaru boisu
よしたね 今日は電波する 枠から直大もらうわ大歓声
Yoshita ne kyō wa denpa suru waku kara chokudai morau wa dai katsusei
(burn out na na uh！)
(Burn out na na uh!)
what i want to touch down
(燃やせ 革命 アップデート hey)
(Moyase kakumei update hey)
go all out
(僕が 覚醒、 逆転 ey)
(Boku ga kakusei, gyakuten ey)
ひとりきり じゃ just kidding 君と だから dreaming
Hitorikiri ja just kidding kimi to dakara dreaming
間違い だらけ 勘違い もして ときめき を リテイク
Machigai darake kamigai moshite tokimeki o rikaiku
ey 失っても なお コンティニュー 支払った 代償 の 自分
Ey ushinattemo nao continue shiharatta daishō no jibun
あの日に… uh してない わけがない 後悔
Ano hi ni... uh shitenai wake ga nai kōkai
胸に 飾る 前向き直せ 歌って (諦め 悪いって？) 信じてくれ
Mune ni kazaru mae muki naose uta tte (akirame waruittte?) shinjite kure
青くも燃える 僕は 炎時は経て どこふうは 心
Aoku moeru boku wa honō toki wa tate doko fū wa kokoro
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ あたしだ さあ お任せ
Dare da dare da dare da atashi da sā o-nimase
(burn out na na uh！) ha～
(Burn out na na uh!) Ha~
抜ける 茨 bae！ make some noise
Nukeru isasaka Bae! Make some noise
有終の美 get up！ hey, raise the bro
Yūshū no bi get up! Hey, raise the bro
賊された 逆境に 下克上 とうとう 役満 あげるわ 大団円
Zokusareta gyakkyō ni gekokujō tōtō yakumono ageru wa daidankai
(burn out na na uh！)
(Burn out na na uh!)
what i want to touch down
(燃やせ 革命 アップデート hey)
(Moyase kakumei update hey)
go all out
(僕が 覚醒、 逆転 ey)
(Boku ga kakusei, gyakuten ey)
ひとりきり じゃ just kidding 君と だから dreaming
Hitorikiri ja just kidding kimi to dakara dreaming
間違い だらけ 勘違い もして ときめき を リテイク
Machigai darake kamigai moshite tokimeki o rikaiku
ey 失っても なお コンティニュー 支払った 代償 の 自分
Ey ushinattemo nao continue shiharatta daishō no jibun
あの日に… uh してない わけがない 後悔
Ano hi ni... uh shitenai wake ga nai kōkai
胸に 飾る 前向き直せ 歌って (諦め 悪いって？) 信じてくれ
Mune ni kazaru mae muki naose uta tte (akirame waruittte?) shinjite kure
青くも燃える 僕は 炎時は経て どこふうは 心
Aoku moeru boku wa honō toki wa tate doko fū wa kokoro
誰だ 誰だ 誰だ あたしだ さあ お任せ
Dare da dare da dare da atashi da sā o-nimase
(burn out na na uh！) ha～
(Burn out na na uh!) Ha~
抜ける 茨 bae！ make some noise
Nukeru isasaka Bae! Make some noise
有終の美 get up！ hey, raise the bro
Yūshū no bi get up! Hey, raise the bro
賊された 逆境に 下克上 とうとう 役満 あげるわ 大団円
Zokusareta gyakkyō ni gekokujō tōtō yakumono ageru wa daidankai
(burn out na na uh！)
(Burn out na na uh!)
what i want to touch down
(燃やせ 革命 アップデート hey)
(Moyase kakumei update hey)
go all out
(僕が 覚醒、 逆転 ey)
(Boku ga kakusei, gyakuten ey)
ひとりきり じゃ just kidding 君と だから dreaming
Hitorikiri ja just kidding kimi to dakara dreaming
間違い だらけ 勘違い もして ときめき を リテイク
Machigai darake kamigai moshite tokimeki o rikaiku
ey 失っても なお コンティニュー 支払った 代償 の 自分
Ey ushinattemo nao continue shiharatta daishō no jibun
あの日に… uh してない わけがない 後悔
Ano hi ni... uh shitenai wake ga nai kōkai
胸に 飾る 前向き直せ 歌って (諦め 悪いって？) 信じてくれ
Mune ni kazaru mae muki naose uta tte (akirame waruittte?) shinjite kure
以上がこちらで調べた情報です。いかがですか？
So that's everything I've got so far. What do you think?
ここは、大空警察。
And so, here she visits the Oozora Police.
数々の難事件を解決してきた優秀な警察から、今回の事件に関するさらなる情報を得るべく、探偵は警察署を訪れていた。
With their stellar track of solving mysterious cases like this one easily, she hopes that they can give her some leads.
バカ、アー。事件の捜査は我々プロに任せとけばいいんだよ。
I think you should leave the investigating to the professionals.
何？被害者の服に魔力の痕跡があったって？
I mean, magical residue on the victim's clothing?
そうダ！そんなバカな話があるか。
Yes! That is very silly!
こいつ、次「自分自身が凶器かもしれない」とか言い出すんじゃないですか、署長。
Next, she's going to tell that SHE'S actually involved and might be the murder weapon.
それだ！
Wait, that's it!
こいつ今、自分が凶器だって自白した？
Did she just confess to be the murder weapon?
よく分かんないっす。
I'm not sure.
ボクが言ったのはただの冗談で…
What I said was just a joke...
もしかしてボク、無意識のうちに真実をつかんではいたのか！？
Could it be that I subconsciously grasped the truth?!
お前天才か！？
You're a genius?!
おや、これはいよいよ事件解決になってしまうのか？
Oh my, could this possibly mean the case is solved?
事件解決しちゃった！
I solved the case!
違う違う、私は凶器じゃないですよ。
No, no, I'm not the murder weapon.
異議あり！さっき自白しただろ！
Objection! You confessed just now!
私が言いたいのは、この事件には別の古代兵器が関わっているかもしれないということ。
What I mean is, maybe another ancient weapon is involved in this case.
だから布に魔力が残っていたんだ。
That's why magical residue was left on the cloth.
なんだ、そういうことか…
I see, so that's how it is...
僕が事件を解決できたと思ったのに…
And I thought I was the one who solved the case...
まあ次がんばれよ。
Well, do better next time.
でもなぁ、現場の近くで変なものを見たっていう報告も届いてるんだ。
But we've also gotten reports of people seeing strange things near the crime scene.
その魔力の痕跡とかやらが超人的な力によるものだっていうなら…変な幻覚が見えた人がいるのもそいつの影響ってこと？
If those magical traces are due to superhuman power... does that mean the people seeing strange hallucinations are affected by it too?
それはまだ分かりませんが、謎は必ず解いてみせましょう。
I'm not sure yet, but I'll definitely solve the mystery.
じゃあうちの捜査資料を持ってっていいよ。
Then you can take our investigation files.
民間人にあげちゃダメっすよ！
You can't give that to a civilian!
でもこいつさぁ、なんか天才の匂いしね？
But this one here, she kind of smells like a genius, doesn't she?
さっきはボクのこと天才って言ったじゃないですかぁ…。
You called me a genius just a moment ago...
どんな情報でも助かりますよ。
Any information would be helpful.
ただし！資料が欲しいなら、タダというわけにはいかんな！
However! If you want the files, it's not going to be free!
これ、また歌う流れですか？
Are we singing again?
おれは知らない 何も知らない
I don't know anything, I know nothing at all
何も見てない 誰も見てない
I haven't seen anything, nobody's seen anything
空を見ても 見えない夜の 欠けた月に
Even looking at the sky, in the unseen night, at the waning moon
嘘に 嘘に 嘘に
Lies, lies, lies
これはなんだ それは何処
What is this? Where is that?
ここは魂 それでよろし
This is the soul, and that's just fine
走る 逃げる 見なす
Run, escape, look away
月の 欠けた 場所へ
To the place where the moon is waning
もう3番目ならなく
If it's already the third one, it doesn't ring
さぁ咎めなく 衝動おさまらず
Come now, without blame, the impulse cannot be contained
なぜか なぜか 知らぬ
Why, why, I don't know
最悪だ 五臓六腑を吐いて濡れ踊れ
It's the worst, throw up your insides and dance wetly
嘘ついてが なんねなんでつってなんか
Telling lies, why why saying something something
最悪だ どうもこうもしねぇよ勝手にしやがれ
It's the worst, do whatever you want, I don't care
嘘ついてが やれも本当最悪だ
Telling lies, doing it is truly the worst
寝ても覚めても突き纏う 見える意思きの裏側に
Whether sleeping or waking, it clings, on the flip side of visible intent
大きく開く黒い穴 分かり 分かる 分かる
A huge opening black hole, I understand, I understand, I understand
許す 許せぬ 許す 許せぬ
Forgive, unforgivable, forgive, unforgivable
かわいい 怖い
Cute, scary
リンゴ ゴリラ ラクダ ゴリラ ラクダ ラボラ ラマダン
Apple, gorilla, camel, gorilla, camel, laboratory, Ramadan
私たち 絶対に見てません 知ってません 聞いてません 知ったこっちゃありません
We definitely didn't see anything, don't know, didn't hear, none of our business
視界を一石二鳥に一つ 許さるざる思考をあざ笑うように 包んで生きていこうじゃありませんか
Let's wrap up and live on, mocking thoughts that cannot be forgiven, all in one fell swoop
孤独など持たず
Without holding onto things like loneliness
今日さえ意味もなく 映画館に満足
Today too, meaninglessly satisfied at the cinema
だから だから だから 最高だ
Therefore, therefore, therefore, it's the best
脳がこうかしてんだぶっ壊して叫べ
My brain is hallucinating like this, smash it and shout
最悪だ なんねなんでつってまこまこ離れて最高だ
It's the worst, saying why why, separating completely, it's the best
鼓膜でけっこう勝手に生き足れ
Living however you like with your eardrums
最悪だ やれも本当最高だ
It's the worst, doing it is truly the best
昔々のおまいら 向き向き身のひとだから
You guys from long ago, you're the kind of people who...
無際無限の生まれ月 それが それが それが
The birth month of infinite boundaries, that is, that is, that is
無関心に押し寄せる あんたもあたしも関係ない 無関心に押し寄せる 楽しくやってりゃもう満点
Crushing in with indifference, you and I have nothing to do with it. Crushing in with indifference, if you're having fun, that's already a 10/10
勝手にやってりゃ問題なし それは知らない 何も知らない 何もいない 何も
No problem if you do it on your own. I don't know that, I know nothing, nobody is there, nothing
聞けない 何も言えない
Can't hear, can't say anything
うわつく甘い街の喧騒
Due to the hustle and bustle of a sweet, floating city,
故に感情線は渋滞
the emotional lines got congested.
「僕に関係ない」とか言って
After saying, "That doesn't concern me,"
心模様 白く染まって
my heart pattern is dyed white.
超的な力が殺人事件に関わっている？
A supernatural occurrence, happening in a murder case?
いやいやそんな、ねぇ？
That's just unbelievable.
にわかには信じがたいが、今の手がかりから推理するとそういうことになる。
She had a hard time believing it, but all the hints said otherwise.
まだパズルのピースがピタリとはまらないこの不思議で奇妙な事件。
Still, there were pieces of this puzzle that refused to fit,
探偵は信頼できる情報源に頼ることにした。
so the detective turned to a reliable source for help.
あっ、来てくれたー
Hey, I'm glad—
…なんで君達まで？
—And why are you guys also here?
ゼータが来るって聞いたから、アーニャにちょっかいかけてやろうと思って！
We heard Zeta was coming over, and decided to bug ya!
はいはい。
Yes, yes, I see.
もー！つれないなぁ。
Aww, come on!
それはそうと…ゼータ、何かつかめた？
Anyway, Zeta, did you find anything?
もちろん！優秀なシークレットエージェントなので！
Of course! I'm not an elite secret agent for nothing.
イナの描いた似顔絵と大空警察の資料から、被害者の身元を特定できたよ。
Between the portrait from Ina and the files from the Oozora Police, I've been able to positively ID the murder victim.
でも…ちょっと変なんだよね。
But... what I found is weird.
変？
How so?
被害者の履歴を調べたところ、その人物は何百年も前の時代の人だったんだ。
Well, when I investigated their history, I found that they actually lived centuries ago.
でもその人物が、数日前になぜか死体で発見された…話がつながらないんだよ。
So how they were also somehow murdered just days ago... it doesn't make any sense.
アーニャからもらった情報に間違いがあったとか？
Did you perhaps confuse your information? Or...
なるほど、やっとつながってきた。
Actually, things are finally starting to make sense.
一人の被害者が、過去と現在で二度死んだことになる。
A victim caught between two times.
誰かが時間と次元をねじ曲げて、そんな状況を作り出した。
One who died in two different ways.
なかなかできることじゃない…
Not many exist who can cause time and dimensions to warp in a way to make that possible...
でも君なら可能でしょ。
...but you're one of them.
さすがは名探偵。
Well done, detective.
ちょっと時間がかかりすぎかな。
Took you long enough.
危うくネタばらしするとこだった。
I was this close to telling ya the whole thing.
レイネが書いてくれた、この匿名の手紙もいいヒントになったよ。
You helped enough with this "anonymous" letter about the murder.
えっ、バレてた？
O-oh, you figured out that was me?
書き方のクセで分かる。
I recognized your writing style.
待って、どういうこと？ムーナと被害者にどんな関係があるの？
W-wait, I don't get it. What does Moona have to do with the victim?
ムーナは、別の時空で殺された遺体を我々がいるこの時空へ移動させたんだ。
She took a murder victim from another space and time, and moved them into our dimension.
ゼータが特定した人物は、この世界線における同人物ってこと。
The one you IDed was this universe's version of the same person.
えー、おっけー。でもどうしてそんなことを？
Uh... okay. But then why?
理由も気になるけど、それより確かめたいことがある。
That is an important question, but there's one I want answered even more.
ムーナが…私にあの夢を見せたの？
Are you... responsible for my dreams?
それは違う。
No.
あなたがあの夢を見ていることを知って、私はあの夢が生まれる根源を調べてみた。そして見つけたのが、次元の向こう側から声を届けようとする魂。
After I learned about your dreams, I used my powers to search for the source of them. I found a spirit reaching out from time and dimensions.
私はその魂のために橋渡しをしてあげただけ…。
All I've done is try to help them by making the bridge a little easier...
私も手伝ったよ！というか、私のアイデア。
With my help! I mean, it was my idea...
そう。
True.
ただやり方が悪かったのか、アーニャの見たものが他の人にも見えちゃったみたい。巻き込んだKFPの従業員には後でお詫びしなきゃ…。
Though doing it this way has caused some of what you've been experiencing to leak to other people. We're going to have to apologize to the KFP workers...
でもその魂が、どうして私に声を届けようとしてるの？
But why is the spirit reaching out to me of all people?
それは私に訊くことじゃないない。私が話すべきことじゃない。
It wouldn't be right for me to answer those questions. It's not my story to tell.
あの魂に心を開いてあげて。それだけでいい。
Open yourself up to the spirits, and they'll do the rest.
心をもっと開く方法なら知ってるよ！
I got a way to make yourself more open to spirits!
それって歌？
Is it through song?
え？なんで分かったの？
Huh? How'd you know?
まあ、勘かな…。
Lucky guess...
想い出してた 想い出の中で泣いてた
I was remembering, crying inside my memories.
確かめたい夢と孤独を抱えて笑ってた
I was smiling, embracing the dreams and loneliness I wanted to verify.
この痛みもキスも拭えないドミノに見返してしまいそうな
This pain and these kisses might make me retaliate against the inescapable dominoes,
焦りとか不安が滲んで涙にのまれてしまう
as impatience and anxiety seep in and swallow me in tears.
誰ひとりかけることはないライトニンググラデーション
A lightning gradation where no one is missing.
僕らの想いが音になって繋ぐ こだまさせて
Let our feelings turn into sound and connect, making it echo.
忘れないよ 隠したシークレットライフを
I won't forget the hidden secret life.
あの日僕らは間違いだって取ったんだ としる
That day, we knew we had made a mistake.
飛ばしてしまい この愛しさを 何度も探し出して
Skip it all and keep searching for this preciousness over and over.
君の声を光らせて ここにいるって叫んでくれよ
Make your voice shine and scream that you're here.
その手を離さないで
Don't let go of that hand.
世界に僕だけが取り残されてしま
I was left behind alone in this world...
SNS午前2時
SNS at 2:00 AM,
深夜のアスファルト 裸足で立つ
standing barefoot on the midnight asphalt.
立ち止まり 手放してしまうなら
If I stopped and let go of it all,
心が通じ合えないなら 黒髪を絞り殺してしまうなら
If our hearts can't connect, if we're going to strangle our dark hair...
一人でいたほうが楽に生きられたのかな
Would it have been easier to live alone?
憧れ理想に強く惹かれる 感情が
Emotions strongly drawn to longing and ideals
僕らを巻き込んでしまうのなら
If they're going to sweep us up,
答えて
give us an answer!
狂わせて いく まだ 笑っていたいんだ ぼくらの延長線上の
Drive me mad, I still want to smile, on our extension line
この音が途切れるまで
until this sound cuts off.
孤独の心に描いた色
The color drawn in a lonely heart,
君の出番が待ってる
your turn is waiting.
狂わせて 忘れないよう 鍵鳴らすタイミングを
Drive me mad, so I won't forget, the timing of unlocking the key.
あの時ぼくらは巻き込まれていなかったと知る
Realizing that back then we weren't even involved,
閉ざして しまい込んだ 一線の光探して
searching for a single ray of light shut away inside.
君の声を聴かせて
Let me hear your voice,
ここにいるって叫んでくれよ
shout out that you're here!
その手を離さないで
Don't let go of that hand.
魂に心を向け？簡単に言ってくれる。
Opening up your heart to the soul? Easy for you to say.
探偵になる前の彼女の人生において、他者に心を開くのは危険な行為だった。
In her life before becoming a detective, opening up to someone was dangerous.
今でもその本能は変わらない。
That instinct still lingers.
結局何も進展はなかった。
This was getting her nowhere.
謎はまだ残っているが、彼女はここのところ無理が続いていた。
She still had questions she needed answered, but maybe she had wound herself up too much.
少し休まなければ。
She needed a break.
Hello, everyone! I'm Hatsune Miku, a virtual idol. Well, that's what everyone seems to think, but secretly, I'm -
Hello, everyone! I'm Hatsune Miku, a virtual idol. Well, that's what everyone seems to think, but secretly, I'm—
I wake up to a call, put my frilly outfit on now
It's time I open up my eyes and start the day
I combat 'til the dawn, until every villain's gone, yeah!
A clumsy trip, and now I've fallen to my butt
With my magical phone and a silly little ringtone
I'll shout a magic word and set the world in place
Whatever it may cost, there's no reason to stop
For a world that I cherish and love
Monsters might be a scary foe to fight
But I'll take the stand
If I can stop your tears and wipe them dry
If my pain's a type of cure for peace, I don't mind
I can play as a nurse healing you every day
So what if I might shed a tear, get some bruises?
A wipe is all I need to clean the cherry blush away, ha!
Fighting through the night, but I'm wide awake
It can all be so hard for me to get through the day
Your smile is enough to heal all my aches
Wrapped in a cute band-aid
I can take the pain, fight all day, fill up the syringe with love, heal up the world and go again
And now it's time for the moment you've been waiting for!
One, two, three, ready? Miku, miku beam!
On my own, without anyone to know
How my job's not all rainbows
But then I think about your smile
I'm a magically bright invincible girl
If you need me to heal, go on and call out my name
When you find yourself going down a spiral
I'll bonk away what puts you down, a pink hammer melee, ya!
Fighting through the night, but I'm wide awake
All alone, it's so hard for me to get through the rain
Your smile is enough to make my day
So I stand tall and brave
'Cause I'm not afraid, any pain, I can laugh away, chin up, with love, I'll fight on 'til the end
A a, nemui yo ~
Ah, I'm sleepy~
Bearing through the pain, I try to be brave
As long as you can stay happy, I'm okay
I'm not gonna bend, ha! I can be a cure for peace in your heart
I'm not gonna bend! I can be a cure for peace in your heart,
and play as a nurse healing you every day. Your smile is enough to heal all my aches
all in a cute band-aid
If you're feeling pain, call my name, I'll be by your side 'til I see your smile beam bright again
うりゃおい！うりゃおい！う～ファイター！ スーパーパワフルミクちゃーん！
Urya oi! Urya oi! Super powerful Miku-chan!
うりゃおい！うりゃおい！う～サイバー！ミクミクミク GO！
Urya oi! Urya oi! Miku Miku Miku go!
あぁ、眠いよ…
Ah, I'm so sleepy...
ユメ…だった…？
It was a dream...?
知った。救いのかない形だった、僕の声は
I realized. It was a form without salvation, my voice—
知った。救いのかない赤い血が流れてんだ
I realized. Unsalvageable red blood is flowing.
たらたら遅い来る影ばかり 道で喧嘩すること真上に上がれないよ風
Dripping shadows slow to arrive, fighting on the road, the wind can't rise straight up.
赤く光る場所へ 裸足でかけたら ただ膝をかかえている君がいただから
Running barefoot to a glowing red place, there you were hugging your knees, so—
ENCOUNT! 悲劇ぶった天国へ
ENCOUNT! To a heaven playing at tragedy,
不甲斐ない瞳きっとあのひみつみつめた君のせいだ
cowardly eyes, surely, staring at that secret was your fault.
はやく はやく 身を揺らして 遠い遠い 水面の向こうへと
Hurry, hurry, shake your body, far, far across the water's surface...
知った。救いのかない熱を持った、僕の円環
I realized. My circle, holding unredeemable heat—
知った。潤いのない君の目は見にくかった
I realized. Your moistureless eyes were hard to look at.
酷く 酷く 酷く...
Cruel, cruel, cruel...
汚染としてるその顔に触れてみたかった
I wanted to touch that contaminated face.
ENCOUNT! 悲劇ぶった天国へ
ENCOUNT! To a heaven playing at tragedy...
知ってた
I knew it.
救いのない形だった僕の声は
My voice was a form with no salvation,
散った
scattered,
狂いのない赤い血が流れているんだ
and crimson blood without madness flows.
ただただ襲い来る影ばかり満ちてて掠う言葉たちあがれない夜風灼かるひかる地獄へ裸足で駆けたらただ膝を抱えている貴方がいた
You, who were just holding your knees, were there.
だから encounter！悲劇ぶった天国へ
So, encounter! To a heaven that ruined tragedy,
“いつか嫌って僕を嫌って”
"Someday, hate me, hate me,"
不甲斐ない瞳きっと、
pitiful eyes, surely,
あの日みつめた貴方のせいだ
it's because of you, whom I gazed at that day.
“背を向けた”はやく身を委ねて？淡々水面のむこうへと
"Turned your back." Hurry, surrender your body to the other side of the pale, pale water surface?
“視線違う”知った、救いのない熱を持った僕の炎夏
"Gaze differs." I knew it, my scorching summer with a heat that had no salvation.
散った、憂いのない貴方の瞳は、醜く酷く
Scattered, your eyes with no melancholy were ugly, horribly so.
“強く”
"Strongly"
茫然としているその表情に触れてみたかった
I wanted to touch that bewildered expression.
だから encounter！喜劇ぶった天国へ
So, encounter! To a heaven that faked a comedy,
白い光を見つめていると
Gazing at the white light,
急な痛みに襲われる
I am assailed by a sudden pain.
僕は私を保っていられなくなること
That I can no longer protect myself,
それこそこの小さな器が証明している
this small vessel proves it.
はじめに、安堵するきみがみたい
First, I want you to find peace,
つぎに、きたいしたい
next, I want to be defiled.
この場所で戦いなど起こっていない。
There was no major battle here.
少なくともこの世界線では…
At least not in this timeline...
だが探偵には分かっていた。彼女が見たものは決して夢ではないことを。
But the detective knew what she saw was no dream.
心の中にはまだ殺戮の匂いが漂っている。
The smell of the carnage still lingers in her mind.
かつての彼女にまとわりついていた、あの匂い。
It's a scent that was, at one time, so familiar to her.
探偵としての生活も今では順調だが、そうでなければあの匂いからは離れることができなかったでしょう。
That stench would still linger on her if the detective's life didn't take a turn for the better.
今でも…あの頃の日々がリアルな夢のようにまとわりつく。
Even now... her days felt more like the real dream.
終わるべくして終わったおとぎ話。
A fairytale. Maybe one that deserved to end.
どこまで行っても彼女は、生まれ持った本質から逃れることはできない。
Because, at the end of the day, she can never run away from her nature.
それでも今は違う。今の彼女には仲間がいる。
But she's not just that anymore. She has friends to thank for that.
それが、別の世界線の彼女とは違う点なのかもしれない。
Maybe that was what separated her from the other version.
もしかしたらあの子は、幸せに生きることのできた世界線があったのだろうかと、
And, maybe... that version of herself just wanted a ray of hope,
そんな一筋の希望を求めていたのだろうか。
to know that there was one timeline where things worked out.
そしてその幸せな世界線というのは、ここではないまた別の世界線のことかもしれない…
Or perhaps this was never about the detective...
考えが頭を巡るものの、答えが出ることはない。
so many thoughts run amok inside her head, but they're forever left unanswered.
なんにせよ、探偵は自身の血塗られた過去を忘れることはないでしょう。
Whatever the case, the detective won't forget her bloody past, but she isn't going to revert to it either.
しかしまた後戻りするつもりもない。彼女はこれからも仲間とともに進む。
She will continue to move forward with her friends,
望んだ結末を迎えられなかった別の自分たちのためにも。
and for all the variants who didn't get their desired ending.
探偵アーニャ・メルフィッサは、明日に向かって生き続ける。
The detective, Anya Melfissa, will keep on living for her own tomorrow.
Anya Melfissa Birthday Live 2023!
Anya Melfissa's Birthday Live 2023!
How did everyone like it?
Oh my goodness!
やっと今年もまいりました、アーニャの誕生日です！いかがでしたでしょうか？
It's Anya's birthday! How was it?
This time, I tried to incorporate a little bit of story into my tree birthday celebration.
And I think it turned out pretty nice, you know?
And also, how was my new original song?
Oh my goodness! How was my new original song?
It was good, wasn't it?
I hope you all liked it, 新曲もね、あの、歌わせていただきましたーー！いかがでしたでしょうか？
I hope you all liked it, and I got to sing a new song too! How was it?
はあ！
Haa!
Oh my god, I celebrated
Oh my god, I celebrated my birthday
my birthday with a lot of friends too this year!
with a lot of friends too this year!
A lot of the girls came to celebrate my birthday and also Detective Anya managed to solve that mission!
A lot of the girls came to celebrate my birthday,
and also Detective Anya solved that mission!
Wow, she's got it!
Detective Anya! Did you guys like Detective Anya as well?
Detective Anya! Did you guys like
Detective Anya as well?
Detective Anya was pretty cool, but not as cool as me!
Detective Anya was pretty cool,
but not as cool as me!
Oh my god, and also special guests! There were special guests!
Oh my god, and also special guests!
There were special guests!
Oh my god, I can't believe I got to sing with Hachinin Miku! Hachinin Miku-chan!
Oh my god, I can't believe I got to sing
with Hachinin Miku! Hachinin Miku-chan!
Oh my god, she was really cute! And also for the narration from my story part with Arein-san narrated...
Oh my god, she was really cute! And also for
the narration from my story part with Arein-san...
Oh my god, with Arein-san also narration story part narration Arein-san ga yatte kuremashita!
Oh my god, with Arein-san also narration
story part narration Arein-san ga yatte kuremashita!
Arigatou gozaimasu! Miku-chan tomo utatta shi yama mori dakusan deshita ne, kotoshi!
Arigatou gozaimasu! Miku-chan tomo utatta shi
mori dakusan deshita ne, kotoshi!
Oh my god, lots of wild things happening on this year's birthday live! How did you guys like it?
Oh my god, lots of wild things happening
on this year's birthday live! How did you like it?
How did you guys like it? Oh my gosh!
Yeah, I had a lot of fun! But... I would like to make an announcement this year.
Yeah, I had a lot of fun! But...
I would like to make an announcement this year.
It's the usual! Koko de kokuchi ga arimasu! I have an announcement to make! Let me make an announcement!
It's the usual! Koko de kokuchi ga arimasu!
I have an announcement to make!
はい！
Hai!
こちら！
Kochira!
Oh my god! What is that? Who is that? Is that me? Yes, it is!
Oh my god! What is that? Who is that?
Is that me? Yes, it is!
We're releasing some new merchandise to this year!
We're releasing some new merchandise
to this year!
What do we have? Let's take a look at them, shall we?
What do we have?
Let's take a look at them, shall we?
Sostte... hitotsu zutsu mite ikimashou! Mazu wa kochira desu!
Soshite... hitotsu zutsu mite ikimashou!
Mazu wa kochira desu!
Wah! It's a canvas art! Study Time with Anya the Canvas Art!
Wah! It's a canvas art!
Study Time with Anya the Canvas Art!
Oh my god, this illustration is so cute! It's illustrated by Lunar-sensei! Lunar-sensei ni irasuto wo kaite itadakimashita! Kawaii!
Oh my god, this illustration is so cute!
It's illustrated by Lunar-sensei! Kawaii!
The theme is, you know, literary girl! Oh my god, so smart, so intelligent! Bungaku shoujo to iu teima ni natte orimasu!
The theme is, you know, literary girl!
Oh my god, so smart, so intelligent!
Tsugi wa kochira! Study Time with Anya the Notebook! This is... I think this is my first notebook! I've never had a notebook as a merchandise before!
Tsugi wa kochira! Study Time with Anya!
The Notebook! I've never had one before!
Oh my goodness! Please use this lots for all your notes for anything! Iroiro memo shite ne! Orijinaru nouto desu! Demasu!
Oh my goodness! Please use this lots for
all your notes! Orijinaru nouto desu!
To tsugi wa kochira! Wah! It's a pencil case! How cute is that! Pen pouch desu!
To tsugi wa kochira! Wah!
It's a pencil case! How cute is that!
Pen pouch mo hatsu kana? Nouto mo hatsu rashii, pen pouch mo nanto... eh, hatsu desu! Zehi isshoni ne, ano... nouto to tsukatte kudasai!
Pen pouch mo hatsu kana? Nouto mo hatsu rashii,
pen pouch mo nanto... eh, hatsu desu!
Um, use this along with the note, I think they would go really well together, okay?
Use this along with the note,
I think they would go really well together!
Tsugi wa kochira! Kotoshi mo voice ga arimasu! Soshite kotoshi mo, eh, Anya ga daihon wo kakasete itadaite orimasu!
Tsugi wa kochira! Kotoshi mo voice ga arimasu!
Anya wrote the script as usual!
I wrote the script as usual, as usual for every year! I wrote the script for this situational voice, so please get it! Please get it!
I wrote the script for this situational voice,
so please get it! Please get it!
Oh yeah, the voice will be in Japanese, but there will be scripts in Bahasa Indonesia, English, and Japanese!
The voice will be in Japanese,
with scripts in ID, EN, and JP!
Chinamini boisu jitai wa nihongo ni narimasu kedo... etto, daihon mo tsuite, tsuite kimasu! Indonesiago to eigo to nihongo no daihon ga arimasu! Zehi kiite kudasai!
Chinamini boisu jitai wa nihongo desu kedo,
daihon mo tsuite kimasu! Zehi kiite kudasai!
Soshite furusetto kounyuu tokuten wa kochira!
Oh my god! Limited edition has... what is that? A hand-signed autograph! Oh my god, it's the first for me!
Oh my god! Limited edition has...
A hand-signed autograph! It's a first for me!
Anya's first ever hand-signed autograph for limited edition! Please get them!
Anya's first ever hand-signed autograph
for limited edition! Please get them!
Nanto kotoshi wa sain-iri desu! Kotoshi wa sain-iri desu! Nanto nanto nanto...
Nanto kotoshi wa sain-iri desu!
Kotoshi wa sain-iri desu! Nanto nanto...
Hatsu... hatsu desu ne, Anya ga mizukara sain wo shite ne... ne, hatsu nanode zehi minasan kono kikai de getto shite kudasai!
Hatsu desu ne! Please get it in this opportunity!
(First time Anya signs herself!)
Yeah, please get the limited edition! And for the standard edition, it includes a foil-stamped replica autograph, so don't worry if you miss out on the limited edition! Yay!
And for the standard edition, it includes a foil
replica autograph, so don't worry! Yay!
To iu koto de guchtsu shoukai wa ijou desu! That's all for the merch!
To iu koto de, guuttsu shoukai wa ijou desu!
That's all for the merch!
introduction.
And another announcement is that
my original song, the one that you guys heard,
um it's called Enka or Encount by the way.
It will be releasing digitally.
It will be releasing digitally in like a few hours.
It will be releasing digitally at 12:00 AM your timezone at 13th March.
It will be releasing digitally at 12:00 AM your timezone on March 13th.
Yay! Yippee! So in like in in like a few hours, yeah.
Yay! Yippee! So in like, in a few hours, yeah.
Yay, なんとね、デジタルリリース、新曲のデジタルリリースもあります、13日の0時です。
Yay! And the digital release of the new song will be on March 13th at 12:00 AM.
よろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to it!
そしてこの後メンバーシップで配信もするので是非見てください。
And after this, there will be a membership stream as well, so please check it out!
There will be a special encore for members only after this.
So, members, my homies, let's go! There will be a membership only stream after this, so please come and watch, it'll be in 3D by the way.
So, members, my homies, let's go! There will be a membership-only stream after this, so please come watch it. It'll be in 3D, by the way!
So you guys might want to check it out.
Yippee!
Okay, are you guys ready? Are you guys ready?
Well, this live is ending, but we still have membership after this.
So, I will see you guys there for members, I'll see you guys there.
And for non-members, thank you so much for coming and for watching my 3D birthday live, I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Thank you! Thank you!
And I wonder if you guys also posted a lot using the hashtag, I sure hope you guys did.
Yay, thank you so much! And Otsukaresu!
Yay, thank you so much! And otsukaresama!
Bye-bye! Otsukaresu everyone!
Bye-bye! Otsukaresama, everyone!